[Music]
he
uh
[Music]
hello everybody Welcome to episode 50 of
the Oscar vet show so today we complete
a half century it's all thanks to you
thank you so very much I would never
have been able to complete 50 episodes
or reach 50 episodes if it was not for
your viewership and your support so
thank you so much all of you and today I
am doing an
experiment uh if you can see the the
chat I will uh take some questions uh
through live chat or through video chat
so there's a link for you to join and
the rules are very simple you need to
have a decent internet connection your
webcam needs to work and you need to
have decent audio and I will take one
question per per uh per viewer whoever
joins so I already have a number of
people who have joined and I will take
them on one at a time but let's first
take a look at who all is here with us
tonight so let's see who are with us I
can see OAS vs kushal GA rajat Singh
Yash Yash Akash sidhant sidhart Beyond
Heights hit Lin 69 ragav jit Akay Joseph
Rahul amindra Hans vad dongre AR Dives
akhat
shubam him Shaker
Omar great kafir anmol Baba shop akan
Barat Shady narcotics
prar satoo am dilip Karan R Bluebird 03
conqueror YT Isa Sharma himat divid aaim
and so many people Anish Abraham Niha
rotra rishikesh Rahul and too many
people for me to name it's so nice to
see you all great to see you all so
today we will do a Q&A of of
course and I will take some live uh
questions from live chat so guys if you
want me to put you on live chat you your
mic needs to work your uh video also
needs to work so I will Al take uh live
chat
questions so uh let me let me take one
viewer
hello hello sir hi hello sir hi hi sir
hi what what's your name where are you
from Sir my name is bhanu I'm from Jammu
and
Kashmir fantastic fantastic so do you
have a question for me yes sir sir I
wanted to ask sir in our text and vas uh
there they mention about sir
so are they the planets that people LA
to
explain that's an interesting question
so they talk about Locas and all uh I'm
not sure exactly if they are planets or
not because as we know in the ancient
days we did not have space travel we did
not have satellites we did not have
telescopes and all so maybe it is a
various Dimensions that perhaps could
exist beyond the Physical Realm maybe
that is what they were talking about the
different Locas and all so I think there
are seven Locas right seven Locas there
is paal loc and there are higher Locas
as well Etc so I think these are
metaphysical or philosophical Realms of
existence it is not exactly physical I
don't think they were talking about
different planets because these planets
exist in our own plane of existence it's
not in a different dimension a higher
Dimension or anything like that so I
think this is not science this is
spirituality or philosophy and we cannot
mix these two because science talks
about what we can observe and what we
can detect and spirituality philosophy
talks about things that we cannot be we
cannot actually observe or detect so I
think the Locust they talk about are
non-physical Realms of existence which
science cannot prove exist or don't
exist so I think that would be your
answer yes does it make sense yes sir
sir all
right I should
read oh I I think I have a book
recommendation video on my channel so
it's I think one of the First videos I
made I made so I think you should take a
look at that and U it I talk about
history as well as quantum mechanics and
physics and all that so you will get
some ideas over there all right thank
you sir sir I am very happy thank you so
much thank you thank you so much for for
being here yeah thank you thank you
bye-bye okay I'm going to uh take some
other other
people uh who do we have here
hello
hello hi what's your name where are you
from hi I'm abir I'm from
Bal okay do you have a question for me
yeah I wanted to ask uh what if India
launches like missiles uh Armed Forces
like does an attack on China and
Pakistan at the same time like tomorrow
so what consequences will India face
like and what events will
happen well there are consequences if
there's an action there's going to be a
reaction the question is does India have
the military capability to take on two
such countries at the same time the see
we can certainly deal with Pakistan we
can but what about China China is a much
larger country they have a much larger
economy like like multiple times of our
economy they have been investing for the
past 30 years plus in their military
might so yes we can launch missiles we
can uh you know wipe out a few cities
Etc but what will we gain by doing that
we need to have a long-term objective
and we need to pursue that objective so
if we launch a few missiles we we
flatten Pakistan and we hit a few
Chinese cities okay maybe we can deal
with Pakistan maybe we'll flatten
Pakistan it's over but what about the
Chinese and what about the world what
will the world say about this you cannot
just do this sort of um launch any
unprovoked attacks on countries there
need to be uh justifiable reasons for
going to war and all that so the first
question is we don't have justifiable
reasons as of now for going to war
there's no red line that has been
crossed secondly if we do that are we
able to then later defend ourselves when
the Chinese also launch missiles so
these are the questions we need to
consider and that's why it is not
advisable to take any such rash action
right now until we reach a certain cap
level of capability militarily and also
the Chinese have not crossed any
thresholds any red lines so we just
can't do that as of as of now right does
that make sense yeah that answers the
question thank you so much thank you for
the question thank you for being here
yeah thank you thank you all right
bye okay who else do we have
chandana
hello hello sir hello how are you doing
what's your name where are you from
chandana right I'm chandana I'm from
Karnataka Karnataka okay wonderful so do
you have a question for me yes sir I
have a question that I have read
somewhere that West Pakistan sorry
Pakistan came with a proposal to to link
Pakistan with Bangladesh and Gandhi was
uh appointed for this so that's why
natam Goods has killed him like that I
read it
somewhere okay okay so what's your
question sir uh I okay yeah I think
there was a proposal or some kind of
request or some kind of Desire from
Pakistan to have some sort of
connectivity between East and West
Pakistan why India and I'm not sure if
it was considered seriously or not maybe
Mr Gandhi was Mr Gandhi was always in
favor of whatever Pakistan requested so
we know that uh so it could be one of
the reasons why Mr God chose to
assassinate Mr Gandhi I think Mr God had
had written a
full account of why he did what he did
why he assassinated assassinated Mr
Gandhi okay so
so I'm I'm gonna have to mute
you yeah okay so so what I think
is okay I'm going to keep you muted for
now so the thing is uh Mr God did write
a full account of the reasons for which
he assassinated Mr Gandhi I am not sure
if this was part of that but he
definitely had a list of reasons and the
main thing was that Mr Gandhi had
betrayed his nation and his people and
that's the reason why he did this I
think I have not read it in its entirety
so I think that there's a it's a it's a
complex thing but but Mr God has given a
proper account of I mean not a proper
account but his version of why he did
that so maybe this was part of it I not
really uh entirely sure about whether
this specific thing was part of that or
not right CH so thank you for your
question thank you
sir
bye okay let's take some more I have a
lot of people here nice to see that okay
I'm going to take Arian Rishi now I'm
going to add Arian hello Arian you
doing I'm
fine uh I can't hear
you could you speak a little
louder are you hearing now yes I'm
hearing you where are you from Arian sir
I from jnk J and
Kashmir fantastic nice nice you're the
second person from there so what's your
question Arian my question is that uh
sir what is the future of India in uh
the field of nuclear power and Sol power
in the next 50 or 60
years so I I would say that um India has
a very good future in the field of
nuclear power as well as Renewable Power
solar power Etc uh India has had a
nuclear power program since the 1950s I
believe and India has advanced I mean
India has a significant amount of
technological ADV advancement when it
comes to nuclear power we are also
investing in thorium uh I think there's
research which is being done in thorium
reactors as well how to
generate uh electricity Etc using
thorium reactors the thorium cycle so I
think uh India needs to invest more in
that because it's clean energy as long
as you know how to use it so nuclear
power India I think I think has good
future and when it comes to solar power
India has it's one of the best places
where you get a lot of sunlight almost
throughout the year except for a few
months during the monsoon and places
like the tar desert Rajasthan Etc get a
lot of sunshine even during the monsoon
so I think India has a very bright
future when it comes to solar power
generation so and it is something that
we need to invest in clean energy so
that we don't uh thus far I think we we
uh rely a lot on burning coal for
electricity so now Mr Modi has started
this I don't know what he calls this
Aban but there is a significant uh push
for for solar power so I think India has
a very good future in
this right so does that answer question
sir yeah yes sir sir one more thing sir
according to you sir uh sir
uh in almost how many years India will
achieve fion
reactor uh right now nobody has
succeeded in uh creating a working
Fusion reactor Fusion is something that
people are pursuing it one hopes that
they will achieve this in the next 5 10
15 years the Chinese are trying it
they're calling it an artificial sun
experiment the Americans are doing the
Europeans the Europeans are also doing
it I'm not sure if India is is currently
pursuing Fusion as a source of power but
uh so India I as far as I know is not
pursuing this as of today but some other
countries are doing it and as of today
nobody has succeeded in using in in
creating a sust in creating a
controlled uh fusion reaction on Earth
so so it's something that's for the
future but it's certainly
possible all right Arian thank you for
your questions thank you you very much
thank you
by okay whom do I call now I'm going to
call
parama hello hi sir I am a big fan of
yours thank you so much thank you so
much so where where are you from barama
I'm from uh West Bengal a place a small
place called chaga I'm from West Bengal
so uh basically I watch all of your
videos and I always wanted to say you
just one thing that I'm a huge fan but I
also have a question for you too yeah
please tell me yeah yeah the my question
is like the original writer of
Mahabharata was vas and when he wrote
Mahabharata it was like 8,800 verses but
soon after it was the first book was
known as Jam or the victory after a few
years years it became bharata with
50,000 verses and after few years it
became Mahabharata with one lak verses
so my question is what is the original
because most people say that there are
many stories or many verses which are
little bit adulterated or fictional so
what's your thought on this
sir so the origins of the Mahabharat we
know that the original author I mean as
per our tradition has been vavas G but
uh the entire path that this uh that the
literature has taken is kind of shrouded
in mystery we kind of have lost the the
story of the evolution of this text like
you said it was a smaller text Just J
later and eventually it became
Mahabharat and as you know there are
lots of different versions of the
Mahabharat even outside of present day
India you have a Thai version of the
Mahabharat you have a balines version
and in Indonesia and other places you
had other versions as well I think even
the cambodians have their version of
Mahabharat and there are different
stories in there which are certainly not
there in the v vas version of the
Mahabharat so this is something clearly
that happened many thousands of years
ago and over the years people have added
certain things to it people have uh
added their only
interpretations and certain other
embellishments and so on so that's how
it has evolved over such a long period
of time the Antiquity of the text is
evident from the fact that it has
evolved so much over the time but
unfortunately as we know our historians
have not looked into this they have not
tried to trace the proper lineage of
this text and that's why this is
something that is going to be
a a matter for a great deal of research
in the future yeah that's what I can
unfortunately we don't have a definite
answer for that but it's a fascinating
topic of research also sir can I ask
another question go ahead yeah I just
think that do historians have the power
to change the complete history and have
their own perspective towards the whole
Community or the society do they have
this
power anybody who uh who creates an
original work a writer an author a
historian anybody who creates something
has the power to change perceptions to
shape the way the world looks
at the way the readers look at the world
and if you are sign uh sufficiently
influential then you can certainly shape
the worldview of a significant portion
of Humanity now historians see the thing
is that every individual has a certain
perspective and every individual has a
certain amount of bias everybody
including me I you know what my bias is
I am very much Pro India and uh so so
everybody has biases we have to
recognize this fact and many people they
are paid to have a certain slant in
their history as we know as we know so
yes historians certainly can influence
people's minds and they can certainly
shape an entire worldview of a Nation
today as we know our our um our I mean
we have all been students we have gone
through the through the entire grind of
the education system and we grew up
believing a certain version of history
now later we realize it was not
necessarily correct so yes they have
done that they have the power but today
because they no longer have the Monopoly
on History that's why the power is wiing
so today the truth is coming up yeah
yeah yeah yeah thank you so
it's such a nice to meet you thank you
nice to meet you as well thank you so
much for for your question thank you bye
yeah thank yeah
bye okay who else do we have okay I
think amod wants to come I I will I will
take everyone Hi amod hi amod where are
you from Sir hello sir sir I'm from
Maharashtra Maharashtra very nice very
nice what's your question sir what's the
question sir I want to ask U the how
European languages are connected to
and how they are originated and is there
any major ancient language group other
than Slavic German and
Latin okay okay good question good
question so you know when these uh
Europeans first came to India about 500
or so years ago uh this they they came
to India to colonize India and to
extract the wealth out of India now this
British uh guy the these people who came
to India they they were eyeing India's
temples so they want they knew that
people donated enormous amounts of money
and wealth to the temples and that's
what they coveted they wanted that and
that is the reason why they started
learning Sanskrit so that they could uh
study Temple Records and understand how
much wealth is there in each Temple what
are the what is what is the kind of
wealth that comes in every year and so
on so that is the reason why they
started learning Sanskrit and that when
they started learning Sanskrit they
realized they could see that there are
so many similarities with European
languages such as Latin such as
uh French English Greek and so on there
are significant
similarities and it is very clear it was
very clear to them that Sanskrit is a
far older language than any language
that is currently present in Europe and
later this entire thing was twisted
around and they said that Sanskrit came
from outside of India and so on that's
the Arian Invasion myth so that is the
linkage between Sanskrit and the
European languages it is called the Indo
European language family so Slavic is
part of that the Slavic languages are
part of that the Scandinavian languages
the uh which are descended from ancient
Viking languages those are part of it uh
the romance languages such as Latin such
as U French Italian Etc are part of that
and almost all the Germanic languages
English Icelandic German and so on and
so forth all of these languages are part
of the Indo European language family and
to the east the Indian Northern Indian
languages and also uh many Southern
Indian languages have elements of this
and even Persian and so on are part of
that so it's an
enormous language family lots of
languages hundreds of languages and
dialects and so on so that is the
connection I mean you can look it up
online there are so many words that are
so similar between all of these
languages right and Sanskrit is the
oldest Indo European language that we
know of the some historians and
researchers try to claim that there are
older languages than Sanskrit in the
Indo European language family but that
is all nonsense that is just because of
their the consensus that they create
politically that they are able to claim
such a thing so so yeah so that's the
answer does it answer your question
yes sir thank you sir thank you so much
for your question nice to meet you and I
will let you go now thank you so much
thank you
sir all right who else do we have okay
ktia will come
now uh hello sir hello hello
hello I'm actually fine I will not call
myself a fan as much as a look up to you
as an idol the things that you're doing
for our nation is pretty admirable and I
guess everybody else should follow as
well in the footsteps thank you thank
you yes sir so so the question I wanted
to ask sir is that uh I know you uh so
so I I'm not really um I I'm not really
an economic student but uh so I got
myself interested into economics and I
started to learn a little bit about
capitalization capitalism and
privatization so sir uh I really like
the American model I want to I want
India to incorporate some of the aspects
of it if not all but sir uh so
considering America's impact on the
world so so America's M1 money stock and
dollars has been has been rising up a
very very high amount uh in the last uh
year because uh and and due to that
there's a very very big risk of
hyperinflation happening in the world
and considering the USD standard of the
world which is deviating from the gold
standard of the world right so so would
India be very very negatively affected
considering that us is one of the major
trade partners of India and apart from
that China is is still on India's head
so how should India cope with
that so it is always a risk when you
have a certain currency that is
underpinning the entire global economy
as the US dollar is doing right now now
the now originally the US dollar was
pegged to the gold rate so it was a gold
backed currency I think it was Richard
Nixon I believe or someone like around
the time who yes who delink uh the US
currency from the the gold standard so
it became a fiat currency and today the
Americans are just printing dollars and
that obviously if you know even the
basics of Economics you know that that's
what causes inflation and today uh the
Chinese are trying to push their
currency in certain places as the
standard and all so there is this tussle
going on this kind of tug of
war and the US economy is not quite on
very good ground the American debt to
GDP ratio is ridiculous they have
accumulated enormous amounts of debt
especially since the Obama regime so yes
it is a problem it is something that
could cause a significant financial
crisis in the future because that amount
of debt to GDP ratio is unsustainable
actually I don't know how they're going
to rectify that and because their
currency is the currency that underpins
the entire world's economy so that means
that if their economy crashes it's going
to it's going to trigger a chain
reaction across the world so I think
that one of the ways you can uh insulate
yourself to some extent is to buy
reserves of other currencies and the
other thing is you can you can hold or
stock a significant amount of gold
thousands of tons of gold India is the
country that has the most gold reserves
I think in the population not the
government the Indian population is the
uh largest consumer of gold globally I
think so there are certain things the
Indian economy can do to the Indian
government can do to insulate India from
such a shock which could happen right so
sir would I add on to my question a
little bit yeah please go Ahad yeah yes
sir so sir if you know Robert kosaki the
writer of Rich D po D yes sir so he
actually predicted that in this month
only the the hyper that the American
economy is going to have a very big
crash even larger than the 2008
Financial CR crisis as well so sir even
even they're predicting that Bitcoin
will come down and stuff like that so we
can even not put our faith in
cryptocurrency as of right now and it's
very very late to actually and and I'm
not a very suitable uh you know
financial adviser for my parents as well
so I guess uh so sir uh and so what can
the Indian government do in in in such a
sense right so you have to see that how
the Indian economy will protect itself
so that everybody does not fall into
like Oblivion and the world does not
come to an end I guess so I think the
Indian government is trying to uh kind
of ban cryptocurrencies right we have
the the RBI has prohibited people from
uh from purchasing or having
cryptocurrency and so on and I think
India has very uh very significant
reserves of foreign currency the Euro
and dollars as well Etc so that could to
some extent uh that could to some to
some extent insulate India from a shock
like that and also India has gold
reserves significant gold reserves so I
think that's what the Indian government
has done is doing has done of course I
am not an economist that is one thing
that I don't really know very very
deeply so I could not answer this in
further detail great depth but uh I
think the Indian government is doing
what we can I think we have one of the
highest reserves of foreign currencies
in any economy in the world so I think
we are doing what we can maybe in the
future we can do something more than
that we can we love to see about that
well thank you sir that was it was
really nice nice meeting you I guess
everybody else will fall in as well nice
meeting you as well thank you so much
thank you bye bye
bye all right all right who next who
next who next let us call shubam shubam
has been waiting patiently hi sham hi
nice to meet you nice to meet you as
well where are you from uh I live in
Youngstown Ohio but I'm from
Nepal fantastic oh you're a nepales
brother of our to meet you please tell
me what's your question uh sir can you
explain a little about Bose and fmy
particles okay so there are two kinds of
Statistics in physics B Einstein
statistics and for D statistics in B
statistics all the particles can occupy
the same Quantum state in FID statistics
um you have a different kind of behavior
of the particles so the bosons other the
particles that do not need that don't
Josel for space they all can uh can
occupy the same Quantum State and that's
why uh their properties are different
very different from the Fons so bosons
uh so the particles that obey the Bose
statistics or Bose einan sta statistics
are called bosons These are the force
carriers these are the mediator
particles such as the gluons and the
photons uh Etc so these are the force
carriers the gluons carry the U are the
are the mediators the force carriers of
the strong nuclear force the photon is
obviously the force carrier of the
electromagnetic force and the
hypothetical graviton is the force
carrier of the gravitational force now
when it comes to Fons they that's a very
different kind of
particle uh species so to say yeah so
the the particles that that constitute
matter these are the Fons so these are
the ones that for obey the FID
statistics and the PO exclusion
principles so that is a little bit in in
in short about Boson Fons and those two
stat those two kinds of Statistics sir
one more question please go ahead yeah
so why don't we study proof-based
mathematics why are we more into problem
solving in our school and high
school uh that's a good question so if
you are into pure mathematics then you
would go into proof-based mathematics uh
very very U uh conceptual fundamental
mathematics but when you are learning
mathematics at the school level you need
to First first start with the building
blocks which are the uh numbers ones and
twos and threes so you need to add them
subtract them divide them multiply them
so that's how you build up your
intuition for mathematics and only after
you uh Master arithmetic addition
subtraction all that and maybe some
algebra trigonometry geometry and so on
that's when after a few years after a
certain number of years you have the
requisite amount of mathematical
intuition to D to dive deeper into
mathematics and that's where you go into
fundamental proof-based mathematics
which is quite abstract actually if a
lay person were to see it it will not
even look like mathematics it looks like
Greek and all that you know so so it's
something that's very deep and Abstract
it takes time to reach that level of U
of thought and abstraction so that's why
at the at the school level Etc you just
learn arithmetic in the basics that's
why it's thank you thank you nice to
meet nice to meet you nice to meet you
thank you so much
bye okay Shia Gupta
hello hello sir
s thank you so much thank you so much
where are you from sir sir I am I am
from jamshedpur
jarand very nice to meet you very nice
to meet you what's your question so sir
my question is that is there any
scientific theory that aligns with our
Vic yoga system like sat
like is there any scientific theory that
aligns with
it so unfortunately uh there is no
scientific theory that I know of that is
uh uh that is commensurate what with
what we call the Yuga system Etc we
don't even know how long a yoga is
supposed to be there are multiple
researchers who have made multiple
claims some people believe that one yoga
is like 100 million years or God knows
what people have all kinds of beliefs it
it it does not match with what we know
of reality because we know that the
human species Homo sapiens is
approximately 2 million years old and if
a Yuga is 70 million years old or
whatever the some people claim it is
then how do you I mean it doesn't make
sense right because uh Homo sapiens not
even Homo sapiens I think Homo sapiens
is just a quarter of a million years old
so so there is this significant mismatch
right so there is nothing in modern
science that that uh bear
out the Yuga system I am not by any
means saying that the Yuga system is
wrong or something what I'm saying is
that present day researchers have not
been able to figure out what the Yuga
system actually exactly is maybe some of
them have figured it out but there's a
lot of controversy there's a lot of
conflict some people say it's this much
time one youa some people say it's not
something else so as of now there is no
consensus and there is a there is not
enough that we know about to to
conclusively say what a yoga is like you
know okay
sir right any other question yes sir in
once you said in your stream that if
Indian imy wants then it can conquer
Kabul in one day like once you said this
but then why Wen Russia and USA
successful in their
attempts uh Shia who's Shia no Rashia
Rashia you
Russ see it's like this the Russians uh
were
overextended when they when it came to
Afghanistan uh the the the heartland of
Russia is many thousands of kilometers
away from Afghanistan even the Central
Asian Republic they were all United n
that ussi was United then yes the
Central Asian republics were at that
time part of the USSR but the heartland
of the USSR was in the west near Moscow
and uh and the territory is so large
that it is very difficult to
sustain a large contingent of soldiers
or a proper Army and and provide them
all the supplies such as U uh such as
weaponry and ammunition and food and all
that so you know an army doesn't succeed
because it has a great deal of J and all
that an army succeeds only when there is
the sufficient amount of logistics and
all that and that's why there were
overextended and also because they were
not familiar with the terrain in
Afghanistan and also because the
Americans were arming the Afghan
mujahidin with a great they were pushing
in a great amount of arms and ammunition
money Etc so that's the reason why why
Pakistan so that is the reason why
Russia could not succeed uh the American
also have kind of failed and they have
left Afghanistan but it was done on
purpose the Americans could have wiped
out the Taliban in in a in a month's
time if they wanted to they chose not to
they knew that the Taliban were given
shelter in Pakistan in the tribal areas
Etc and so on we know what the
pakistanis were doing they were
Sheltering Osama as well and the
Americans allowed this to happen they
killed Osama but the Taliban was able to
was allowed to survive in Pakistan and
gradually it it made its way back into
Afghanistan so it was all done most
likely
deliberately now when it comes to India
we have the armed forces and we have the
strength of the Armed Forces suff it's
sufficient to wipe out the Taliban in in
a few days in a couple of weeks maybe a
month or two at most you know so I hope
that answers your question okay s s s
one thing I do you have any idea like in
which language did people normally
convert in the and
mahab Sanskrit that's it means talking
also yes absolutely talk originally
India's common language was Sanskrit and
when did they
started in the
CH which language
then uh at that time it was a variety of
prit languages which are upal languages
and the language I think which was
prevalent in the magad region was uh
piali I believe so these are languages
that came much later the original
language of India was vidc or previc
Sanskrit then it became Vic Sanskrit
eventually it became classical Sanskrit
during the paninian era and later you
had a variety of other languages that
emerged and I am sure there were other
languages also during the Sanskrit era
as when did Hindi came being P much much
much much later like it's a very recent
language maybe in the past 500 or
thousand years I taught in I School
books that Sanskrit was only imited to
the bahman class that is absolute utter
nonsense all right okay okay sir thank
you sir great meeting and my friends
would be much
J awesome awesome nice to meet you nice
to meet you siia thanks thanks bye-bye
bye
sir all right who else will come next
who do we have okay yug let's bring in
yug Hi yug how are you doing hello sir
nice to meet you and I seeing that many
young people are joining your podcast
that's great it's awesome I yeah go
ahead yeah yes sir actually I had
question that uh you know Jane M they
always give lots of you know prachin in
that I had one time I listened it and
they said that there were genocide of
Jane people in Tamil Nadu by shitz you
say Hinduism very you know liberal
religion but but on the other hand it's
ironical that genocide of Jan
people so I have never heard of any such
uh I have never seen evidence of such a
thing I have never heard a claim like
that that the Jas were genocided by the
shites I would like to see who has made
actually searched actually I had
searched in my you know internet so I
got it in Wikipedia and that stuff so
and also I want to ask
so s you can
speak so my question is how many people
were killed when did this happen
according to this
claim means they actually I don't know
means I had saw in YouTube so I don't
know but it was said that after 250 BC
and it was written in something in Tamil
literature they had said that and it was
written by Tamil
literature they say that well I am not
aware of of any genocide that happened
in pre-invasion pre-t turkic Invasion
India maybe see people have gone to war
kingdoms have fought each other there
has been violence which is a inherent
part of the the human nature but there
has never been any large scale religious
persecution of anybody in the country
there is no evidence to support that if
one or two texts have been invented to
do that I mean come on where is the
supporting evidence and so there is as
as far as I understand from whatever I
have read and learned I have never come
across any evidence of any genocide you
know what's the meaning of genocide it's
like lacks of people dying if if there
is a war or battle in 200 die you cannot
call it a genocide come on it's one
event so so my point to you is that you
know uh I have never come across any
such claim or any such evidence but I
will certainly since you are telling me
right now I will try and look it up and
I'll try to search for any persecution
of Janss in Tamil Nadu you think right
Tamil Nadu yes madas near that hill was
there yes also one more last question I
want to say and also he also said that
the sh sa Baba was actually an from
Afghanistan a pindari and he came to
probate Islam and to convert
people no I have absolutely I have so so
my answer to you is that I have never
studied the I mean I have never been
interested in this uh person Mr saai
Baba so I don't know anything about him
unfortunately so unfortunately I cannot
answer this particular question
sorry yes sir thank you so much sir for
all right thank you nice meeting you
thank you so much for your questions bye
sir
bye okay who next who is next let's
bring
abinav hi abinav how you doing thank you
very much for giving me this opportunity
to be here I want to ask like how did
life came from non- living substance how
did replicating system form from
non-replicating system that the
scientist called a biogenesis I want to
learn on
that so we don't quite know how this
happened we know that at some point in
our very ancient history in the
primordial early Earth life emerged out
of something we know that the we had
this these interesting mixes of
chemicals on our planet we had
uh so we had very different conditions
at that time the Earth was almost a
hellish place it was very hot and the
atmosphere was very different it was
full of other gases maybe mostly carbon
dioxide there was almost no oxygen at
the time and there was a lot of
lightning there was a lot of bombardment
by meteors and all that meteorites and
so on the hian period they call it so
what people have done what biochemists
have done is that they've tried to
replicate those conditions in a test
tube in a
laboratory with those mixes of gases and
lightning kind of thing and all that
with the electrical Sparks and all that
so they found that it does give rise to
a complex chemistry amino acids and all
that complex carbon compounds but they
have never been able to actually create
a living cell or living organism out of
it so it is still a very big mystery how
life emerged on Earth where did the DNA
come from DNA is a very complex molecule
you know so where where did it come from
where did RNA come from where did the
and so on so so forth so it is still not
known no scientist has been able to
definitively conclusively explain how
did life emerged emerge out of
non-living substances there is even a
theory called panspermia which says that
life Came From Outer Space it it hitched
a ride on some meteor or Comet and it
crashed into the onto our planet and
that's how the our planet was seeded
with the uh with the beginnings of Life
maybe DNA came from outside or or maybe
some organisms were were present on some
of these asteroids or or comets that
impacted the Earth so there's a number
of hypothesis but none of these has been
proven thus far so that's what I can
answer you that the to the best of our
knowledge we still don't know how life
emerged out of non-living
substances and also on bioh Hacks like
cloning and baby designing do you think
it is happening in the shadows and we
don't know about it it is certainly
something that people must be
researching we know the Chinese have
been doing a significant amount of
research in cloning and uh Gene drives
and all that virology
viruses and and so on they have cloned
monkeys they have cloned other animals
maybe they may even be doing it with
human beings we don't know and other
countries may also be doing it but
obviously they will not talk about it
because this is very uh first of all
it's Cutting Edge research it it can
lead to very significant advances not
only in biology but in bio as in the
case of bioweapons as well and secondly
may maybe many of these experiments may
not be very much ethical so nobody will
talk about it but I'm sure many
countries are doing it I'm sure the
Chinese are definitely doing it I'm sure
the Americans too even if they don't
speak about it must be doing it and
other countries possibly as
well right so my last question is that
you are a professional astrophysicist
and Quantum physicist so can you give a
road map for people like me who are
inspired for me and want to pursue that
as a
career well that's that's a very long
career path you have to undergo a
progression of studies you have to first
become strong in mathematics you need to
have the fundamentals basics of physics
right the very Basics from theid rnic
kind of books then you have to study
electrodynamics and uh uh Advanced me
mechanics then move on to Quantum
Mechanics Quantum electrodynamics and so
on it's a very long path I have a video
on this channel in which I have given a
number of book recommendations for
learning Advanced physics so maybe you
can refer to that but it's a I mean to
answer that in detail would take at
least half an hour you know so you could
refer to that video the book
recommendations video right thank you
sir thank you very much for providing
this intera interaction with us and nice
meeting you nice meeting you thank you
so much bye a very
much okay who next Whom Shall I call uh
goam has been waiting very
patiently hi goam hello
siret I want to ask a question ah nice
to meet you sir I want to ask a question
about origin of
andras the origin of Andra people Andra
people so I am yeah please go ahead
please finish your question yeah it said
that t came from Andra people Andra
tribe so I want to ask you how that
origin of Andra
people
Andra I okay yeah I get your question
right what is the origin of the people
of Andra Pradesh the people of Andra
right so uh that is something I haven't
studied in much detail unfortunately uh
we know that during the ancient times
there was a mention of a clan or a tribe
or a community of people called the
andras now U that has been that name has
been given to this state called Andra
Pradesh today which is now Andra Pradesh
and Telangana but what is the origin I
mean we know that all the people of
India of if we go back
sufficiently uh back in time then we all
have a common origin but what is the
actual origin of let's say the Andra
linguistic group The the Telugu speaking
people for instance that is something
that is that I think no historian or
linguist has still being able to answer
so that is something that should be a
topic of of active research among
historians and linguists but it is
not it is not so nobody will be able to
give you a definitive answer neither
historians nor linguists as to what is
the origin of this language Telugu and
of this linguistic group the people who
are now part of the state of Andra
Pradesh so it is something that needs to
be researched there are there are so
many such topics what is the origin of
the Canada people that also nobody is
going to be able to answer the tamils
have their own origin stories about
Kumari kandam and all but that also
again has not been proven we have never
found that lost continent that that they
speak about and so on so the best answer
I can give you is that we Indians are
the original inhabitants of the Indian
subcontinent our ancestors populated the
first came into the Indian subcontinent
about 70,000 or so years ago the Out of
Africa migration and we are the
descendants of that very ancient
population so that is what we know but
the uh Genesis the origin of these
specific linguistic groups and all that
is something that has not been
researched unfortunately so I'm sorry I
am not able to answer that question in
in well conclusively
definitively so my last question is you
said that there was philos Indian
philosophies of J Dharma Buddha Dharma
and charaka so what are we following now
all
Hindus We are following secularism sir
we don't even know what Hinduism is what
Dharma is we don't follow any traditions
we don't follow any rituals uh I don't
know what we are following anymore India
Today is officially a secular country it
is very Hindu phobic country Hindus are
almost like second class citizens so we
are not following any of those
philosophies the jna people will follow
some of the Traditions which is part of
Dharma the both the people will follow
some of the both the Traditions I think
in countries like Thailand Etc Thailand
and parts of Cambodia part parts of
Indonesia there is more respect for
Indian traditions and culture than we
have in India itself so today India is a
confused country we have lost our
connection with our roots and that is
all thanks to this fake philosophy or
ideology of secularism that has been
forcibly imposed upon the Indian
population so I hope that eventually
these things
change uh thank you sir thank you for
your question nice meeting you thank you
bye thank you
sir
right namon let's bring in Naman hi Nan
Nam sir Namaste Namaste where are you
from sir I'm from
Rajasthan Rajasthan all right what's
your question
sir
disc
good
questional
and so
onanon of
indiais Comm Europeans Europe
misis foreign education system education
system English
British
I think 18y
first British I
mean
is
languages local
languages so it can all come back we
will restore our self respect and
dignity
Dem CA
GST which brief
thoughts
um
say
SE
so let's take the
question for
instance
right offic deci
and government
offic
rely
democracy numbers it's a numbers game
very simple disc
yes sir that is how democracy
Works they cannot be allowed to stop the
passing of the
bill
for
we can disagree no problem that is
fine so we have to
analyze
options how is it a bad thing so that is
my
perspective
Cil India originally
civilization nation state westan nation
state it all originated in in the Treaty
of
West
so it is a very artificial kind of thing
actually
natur it is artificially created
thing thank you sir thank you so much
thank you nice talking to
you bye thank you
bye CH who is next who is
next uh let me call in
susant hi
suant good evening sir um I have
actually two questions uh I posted it on
live chat as well but uh I think you
didn't notice it so my question to you
is that in first Ang marata War marat's
won so why didn't they completely
destroy the British Empire that time I
mean
uh at the end of third Ang marata War
British completely destroyed the marata
Kingdom right so why didn't maratas do
the same in first time in
marata so now if I give you the proper
answer then don't hate me for being
anti- marata I am not anti- marata okay
I mean lots of people keep tell me that
you are anti- marata you you don't
recognize the maratas enough and all by
please don't do that I just telling you
the I know I I
had
I'm telling the future audience who will
watch this later you know please just
just listen just hear me out so let me
ask the
question so now the thing is this see
the maratas did win and they did not
eliminate the enemy completely that is a
problem you see again and again and
again in the past 10,000 years of
India's history we have this unfortunate
tendency of trying to show magnanimity
to those who wish to destroy us that is
a pattern of behavior we see again and
again we have forgotten the principles
of our great teacher vishnugupta
chanakya vishnugupta chanaka said when
the enemy is down you to finish that
enemy off because we know that the enemy
wishes to see us dead so how can we let
that person go this this is what
Maharani nayaki Dei G did she allowed
that the terrorist gory to go away uh
this is what PR Chan did this is what so
many did the maratas did they allowed
the British to stay alive to to survive
the maratas even allowed the mugal the
the at least a token uh measure of
survival you know because even after the
maratas had take had conquered the
entire country the mugul emperor at
least in name was still installed in
Delhi so this is something a pattern
that we see I don't I don't know why it
is there because our culture has
produced people like Vishnu who have
given us the right lessons but we have
forgotten their teachings so that is the
reason why because we have forgotten the
teachings of our great teachers like
Vishnu Chiki that's why we have allowed
our enemies to survive and and
eventually
Thrive right so so my next question to
you is if if it's allowed please go
ahead please so so uh I checked on
Wikipedia a few days ago about calculus
and the history of calculus so according
to Wikipedia only one of those basic
calculus laws is uh is originally from
India and rest of them are like not not
from India they're from some Arabic or
some non Indian philosophers have
developed this uh laws and all so what
is the truth is is it just one law or
the original calculus was itself the
idea of
Indians the truth is that calculus was
developed in India uh it is a long line
uh it's not something that happened in
one day or one week or one year it
happened over a very long period of time
there is a long Pro Cycle of development
that leads up to the eventual discovery
of calculus so I think it was the Kerala
School of mathematics that dis that was
the discoverer of calculus um I forgot
the name of the mathematician was it
nilakanta or was it uh
I I don't have it at the top of my head
but it was in Kerala that calculus was
developed at least minimum 100 years
before Newton and lib nits are supposed
to have discovered calculus and it is
very strange that Newton and Li nits
both of these individuals one who was
living in England the other one who was
living in I think Germany I think it is
very strange that these two individuals
discovered calculus inde dependently of
each other in the same year how can that
happen what really happened was that you
had these Jesuit priests who had come to
India and they sought Indian knowledge
they stole India's knowledge of
mathematics Etc astronomy and many other
things they took it back to Europe they
translated the Sanskrit texts into their
languages and that's how and there is
actual evidence for these things there
is evidence for this but it is not
publicized they will never publicize
this so it is these Jesuit missionaries
these Jesuit priests who came to India
they stole India's knowledge they
transmitted it back to Europe not back
to Europe they took it to Europe and
over there the so-called scientists
discovered it and now they are given the
credit for discovering calculus it is
very strange that something as difficult
as as and as complex as differential and
integral calculus was discovered
independently by two people in Europe in
the same year I mean it can never happen
that is nonsense so it is
India
without absolutely nonsense right yeah
so I hope that answer your question yes
and one final question so did uh
britishers and sik Empire of 19th
century of Maharaja Ranjit Singh and all
did they anytime had military conflict
and if has then who was the who was the
winner at least first Ang
I think the first Anglo s war was a sick
uh military Victory if I am not mistaken
I have not studied in very great detail
there were two Anglo sick Wars uh the
first one I think was either a sick
Victory or a stalemate kind of situation
and the second one war the second Anglo
sik war was in
1845 or 49 or thereabouts I don't
remember dates I only remember the
century but the second one was a victory
for the British okay so after Maharaja
rajjit Singh died I think in the 1830s I
think that's when the entire sik Empire
very quickly uh collapsed because there
was no ruler who was of the caliber of
Maharaja Ranjit Singh So eventually
that's why the S Empire uh lost to the
British thank
you thank you for your questions nice to
meet you thanks
bye-bye okay who shall we take next let
me take
um let me take
Karthik hi
Karthik yes pram sir
yes nice to meet
you that I am live with you well here
you are you're live with me what's your
question
sir sir
uh
[Music]
I am unable to hear you Karthik I'm very
sorry I think your internet connection
isn't very good sir am I now
audible yes yes please go ahead ask a
question just a
second sir I was asking have you uh
researched about that Culp vgam you
Idol which is told about that it is 26
th000 year
old I have heard about it but I have not
yet had the time to deep to dig deeply
into this matter so unfortunately I I am
still not properly aware of
it and Sir according to you which was
the greatest uh Indian
empire till
now I think the greatest Indian Empires
are the ones before are the ones that
are not written about for instance you
had the Kota Empire the Kota
Dynasty mapa which nobody writes about
you had the there are many many
dynasties and Empires you know even
before the morian Empire the morian
empire was certainly one of the largest
and most powerful Empires that we know
of it it included most of present day
India plus Pakistan plus Afghanistan Etc
so the Moran Empire was very great but I
think even before the Moran Empire there
must have been I mean who which was the
Empire or the kingdom or
the or whoever it was that built the
entire saasu region the so-called
harapan era of our civilization it was
so large it was bigger than Mesopotamia
and Egypt combined and it was so
Advanced I mean the if you look at the
town planning the city planning it is
superior to Modern Indian cities the
drainage systems were better than modern
Indian cities so whoever did that must
have been incredibly sophisticated and
advanced and we don't even know as of
today which empire which Dynasty which
ruler or rulers it was so I think we
don't know much about Indian history we
have lost a lot of information but from
the ones that we know of I think keska
was one of the greatest the the kusan
Empire also the the Moran Empire so I
would give these two names to answer
your
question right does it make sense what
I'm
saying
once
again okay I'm unable to hear Kik
unfortunately yeah sorry sorry it's it's
gone okay let's take some other
questions let's take some other
questions somad somad
hi hello sir can you can you hear me I
can hear you yes yes how are you doing
I'm great sir I I have been listening to
you from from the time you released your
Mongol Jang jeshan
video so nice of you thank you so much
so my question thank you sir so my
question is what is an ad mixture and
what does David track mean when he says
ancient skeletons of Indians had did not
have Steepy ad mixture and modern day
North Indians have Steepy ad
mixture an ad mixture is a combination
of two different kinds of lineages
genetic lineages so for instance if a
person
has uh European ancestry as well as
African ancestry then you will find an
ad mixture of different genetic lineages
in the genetics of that individual so
that's what an ad ad mixture is now
people I mean these geneticists they say
that Indians that uh that the harons did
not have step ancestry but modern
Indians do have it I mean how many haran
genomes have we analyzed
we have thus far been able to
successfully analyze the DNA of only one
individual from the harapan era they
have been able to extract the N from
only one skeleton so on the basis of one
skeleton how can you claim to have
understood the entire genetics of the
harapan era that is ridiculous and
secondly when they claim that the modern
Indians have step ancestry they are
referring to the yam ancestry the
yamnaya Invaders of Europe now we know
that the yamnaya had a certain
patrilineal genetic lineage called r1b
r1b is The Descendant lineage of the
Indian origin R1 and R
lineages which tells you that the even
the yam the so-called step people were
descendants of Indians they originated
in India and now if you if you if you
give them the title of Step ancestry
that it kind of misleads people because
even the step ancestry hasn't in
ancestry but they will not mention that
so that is the kind of misinformation
game that is being played but if you
look at the facial reconstructions of
the am people they look like Indians we
know they had dark hair they had light
brown skin they had brown eyes they
looked exactly like Indians you know so
even the step ancestry is actually
ancient Indian ancestry so that I hope
aners your
question uh sir my second question was
uh yes sir okay so my second question is
uh is is Brahman a v or a jati because
if you look at ancient Kings like pusham
shunga and you take the pesas they
identify themselves as brahans but their
karma is
chhatria so you know what this is not a
jati it is a VNA Verna is something that
comes from from what activity or or
occupation you have in your life so it
doesn't matter where you are born
whatever your aptitude is I mean let's
say you were born in a so-called sudra
family but you are very strong you're
very active you're great at fighting so
you can become a chhatria if you enroll
in the Army and do well or even if you
are born in a chhatria so-called family
but if you are a scholarly person and
you read and study things and you are an
intellectual Etc then you should be
classified as a Brahman so these are
wers these are not jatis jatis are
lineages jatis are are are ancestral
lineages wers are simply
occupations so that's a different so
those are two different things so like
you said pushia was was was born in a
certain Verna but he was a chria because
he was a soldier and he became a king
that's how it went it's a it's a very
ancient and very complex system and we
have oversimplified it for the sake of
political gains today that's what's
happening
so I hope that answers your question sir
yes sir yes sir sir my final question
today we see uh we we just got saw in
news that India might face electricity
shortage because uh coal Coal storages
are goal reserves of low Less in India
so how could we have avoided this
problem I think we have sufficient coal
reserves in the country we have lots of
mines and all
uh I personally haven't seen this news
but I'm I'm sure you what you're saying
is right there may be some possibility
well what we have to ensure is that we
have to ensure that there is sufficient
supply of coal either from our own minds
or or through the various Imports that
we can arrange so I am sure the
government must have foreseen this and
uh I hope that they have the uh adequate
measures and contingency plans in place
to ensure that there is no such problem
that's what I can
say right
thank you
sir thank you thank you so much for your
questions thanks pleas please do this
more
often certainly
C right thank you thank you bye-
bye okay who else do we have we have
lots of people waiting in the
wings Rahul g
hi uh hello sir thank you very much for
having me on the show and also I'm very
happy I'm very happy to see you live and
I've been following you from past one
month I've actually watched a lot of
videos of yours and I'm very thankful
that you you're there for us to learn so
many things and I'm happy that these
kids are actually coming up and asking
all these questions with to you and also
you're like giving us the great answers
and which is like very logical so I had
two questions I've joted down just one
second so yeah uh could you please talk
about the Multiverse uh and the research
uh around
it so the Multiverse is not a theory
it's a hypothesis so there are two uh at
least two sources of the origin of this
hypothesis one is from the string theory
landscape so in string theory there is a
possibility of 10 raised to 500 or so
different universes so that is one of
the uh reasons why people why phys ists
consider this Theory or this hypothesis
of of there being a Multiverse and the
other is quantum mechanics itself where
the
the the many worlds hypothesis the
everan hypothesis in which every
decision that you take every action that
you take when you have a choice of doing
this or that if you make one choice then
the universe splits off into two I'm
just giving you a very simplified
version but let's say you flip a coin
you get a head then in then the univers
splits off into two branches and there's
a parallel universe that's created in
which you have got a tail and so on so
that's from the multi multiple
worlds hypothesis or or or
interpretation of quantum mechanics that
is due to uh Everett so that is so
that's what the Multiverse is it's it's
a hypothesis which says that there are
multiple universes our our universe is
just one of many universes out there the
problem with this is that there is no
way to either prove it or to falsify it
because we are stuck on this planet we
can look into the universe through
various means through telescopes Etc but
we can only see a certain portion of the
universe the visible Universe the UN the
actual universe may be much much larger
than that and we cannot by any means
look beyond the confines of our universe
is there other Another Universe out
there how do we know because we have no
way of testing it out and therefore this
may be possible this may be a
possibility one cannot discount it but
it is something that is not falsifiable
a scientific theory has to be
falsifiable if it is not falsifiable
then there's no point even talking about
it you know so it's nice for science
fiction movies and M these superhero
movies and all that it's very nice but
it is not something that is a field of
active research is serious active
research unless you're talking about the
multiple the tin interpretation of
quantum mechanics which is something
that is taken a little bit more
seriously okay sir I just had one
question on that because like uh there's
a concept called expanding Universe
right uh because of the big bang and uh
the universe is continuously expanding
so I just had one this this question I
had it from my college days uh nobody
could answer I just just asking you like
I just want to know like in case if the
universe is actually expanding what is
it expanding into because it needs to
have some kind of a space right and if
there is only one Universe it cannot
expand uh I mean that that was my my
question how can it
expand right so this goes at the very to
the very heart of the uh standard model
of physics The Big Bang Theory the
so-called Big Bang Theory so the Big
Bang Theory is a chronology of the
universe it is a history of the universe
what happened at the very beginning then
what was the universe like in the very
early era how did the universe evolve
and so on and so forth how did structure
formation happen Galaxy formation how
did nuclear fusion start Etc and so on
so it is a chronology a history of the
universe but it is not yet able to
explain why certain things happened what
caused the Big Bang what was there
before the Big Bang was there something
else before what is time there are so
many questions that our best theory is
still not able to answer so is there
something that the universe is expanding
into we have no way of answering what we
know is that space time itself is
expanding so when the universe began it
was concentrated into a into a very
small Point that's the best we know it
was either a singularity which is a
point of infinite density or it was
something very close to a singularity
and then something made the universe
expand the it is hypothesized to be a
certain field it's called the inflaton
field and so on so that's a different
thing but something caused the universe
to expand and it is not the universe
expanding into something it is space
time itself expanding so even as we
speak right now space time is expanding
all the time new SpaceTime is being
created out of somewhere what is footing
the bill the energy bill of this we
still don't know maybe it is something
called dark energy which we know exists
and so on so there are many things that
we still don't know our best theory the
standard model and the Big Bang Theory
still can't answer lots of questions so
that is the best answer I can give you
sir yeah thank you very much sir I have
one last question uh there there have
been like iits and IMS for many years so
what exactly the research they are doing
and how is it helping
India that is the 100 CR rupe question
isn't it what research are these people
doing and how is it helping
India well the I it
unfortunately so here's the truth about
the iits
okay they will not like me for like me
saying this if you go to let's say you
go to a specific IIT IIT whatever I'm
not taking any names you go to the I you
will find that there is wonderful
infrastructure there you go to the
auditorium the conference room beautiful
place the best projectors the best
equipment you go to the washroom it's
a$1 million washroom all the beautiful
glass and beautiful tiles and all that
but if you go to the lab you will find
equipment that is 20 to 30 years old now
when you have outdated obsolete
equipment how are you supposed to do
Cutting Edge research so the answer to
your question is that the people who run
the iits these administrators these
bureaucrats who are not scientists they
have the funds but they are investing
the funds where those funds are not
needed they are investing funds in in
building beautiful auditoriums and and
beautiful washrooms Etc but they are not
investing it in the latest equipment and
so on and therefore the professors the
staff the researchers the students they
are not able to do any world-class
cutting Ed research so it is just
churning out
substandard outdated research and that's
what's happening there is no new
invention coming out of the aties there
is no new research coming out of the
itties this is something that you find
over and over and over again in the
entire Indian academic system not just
in the iits even in the universities the
best universities supposedly of the
country it is something I've spoken
about in the past it's very frustrating
so that is the sad situation in the
country right now the entire academic
system is controlled by a nonacademic
non- research bureaucracy who are just
bureaucrats and
even I mean if you look at the way
people are promoted it's all it's more
to do with politics than their actual
achievements or their actual research
output so that is the sad state of
Academia today but to answer your
question in brief there is no real
research that's happening maybe 1% of
the researchers are really good world
class maybe the theoreticians are able
to do real research some of them but the
majority of these academicians and
researchers are are themselves quite
mediocre so that's the situation we are
in right now
unfortunately yeah that's really bad sir
but hopefully things get better future
thank you very much sir thank you so
much nice meeting you thank you so much
thank you bye
bye right let me bring in sanjie hi
sanjie hello sir um I am your audience
from the ranir show I really loved your
Chan I have a question yeah um since you
have preached a lot about the dharmic
culture its sustainability
um do you think we failed moving towards
the West propagating it towards the West
what do you
think were the reasons which did not let
us propagate towards the
West so uh the fact is that there was a
time about 1500 years or so before
before today before the christianization
of
Europe at that time the culture that was
present that was prevalent in Europe was
a manifestation of what we call dharmic
culture so there was a cultural
Continuum across Eurasia from the
westernmost parts of Europe the British
islands all the way eastwards to India
it was a single cultural Continuum you
had very interesting local Regional
manifestations of the same or arching
culture which is called the
Indo-European culture I don't I don't
know if it's a very accurate term but
that's what they call it so the Vic
Pantheon of gods Indra vun Mitra Etc the
same gods are found in Greece ancient
Greece in Rome in the uh Nordic regions
the Vikings they had the same Gods the
Germanic uh peoples also had the same
gods they gave them different names but
the gods were the same the Slavic Gods
also were the same so you had the same
culture everywhere it was spread across
Eurasia then you had the
christianization of Europe which wiped
out violent ently the native culture of
Europe and then this was a very
expansionist kind of culture the
abrahamic religions are expansionist
religions they are exclusivist
supremacist and expansionist and that's
how they were able to capture conquer
large parts of the world and that's the
situation we're in today so the dharmic
culture is not a supremacist exclusivist
and expansionist culture we don't
believe in converting people to over Rel
we don't believe in using Force you want
to do it you do it if you don't want to
do it your life your choice we don't
care so that is the reason why our
culture is today confined only to
certain parts of India not even
throughout the entirety of India that's
your answer yes sir and uh if we if we
were to fix the current uh system of
Science and Technology the learning as
well as research what pointers could you
suggest in the future that could
that uh it will take a significant
amount of reforms it's not going to
happen overnight uh it will not not take
one week one month one month one year
one decade it's going to take at least a
couple of decades it's a long process uh
I have an entire uh video I think uh I
think it was episode 30 or 31
thereabouts in which I have given a very
detailed uh presentation of what the
problems are and what can be done to
some extent to start reforming the
education system so I would request you
to take a look at at that video if you
have the time it's a it's 1 hour plus
video in which I have given all the
details right yes sir thank you so much
thank you so much for your questions
nice to meet you thanks bye nice to meet
you
to swastic hi
swastic can you hear me sir yes sir hi
hi okay what's question sir yes yes I
can hear you I'm from Himachal Pradesh
so nice so starting
the first question is um when we see all
the abrahamic religions their
communities are very much um coin
Centric they all are have the same
beliefs everything same they are very
much less philosophical but they are
very much political so were these
religions actually made philosophical
and then with time made political or the
main thing was political but
philosophies were added with
them so the if you look at the history
of the abrahamic religions the the very
Genesis the very birth of it it is about
one Prophet claiming that he has
received the word of God and then
everybody is supposed to follow it and
there is no yes or no there is no right
or wrong you just have to blindly
believe and follow whatever I say so
it's always been like that from the very
beginning there are three abrahamic
religions that that we know of I mean
that that are in existence and they all
follow the very similar precepts and uh
beliefs so it it is a very political uh
structure it is it is organized in a
military fashion I'm not criticizing it
it's just an observation so that's just
how it is so there is no room for
questioning or dissenting you have to
believe and that's it there is there is
no option there is no alternative you
have to just blindly believe whatever is
written in their books and so on in
Hinduism it's very different you can
question you can even be an atheist they
will not throw you out of a building you
can be lgbtq or whatever and no one
cares you live your life I live my life
so there is no compulsion there is no
Force there is nothing so it's a very
different culture so so that's why you
find this significant difference between
dharmic culture and the abrahamic
religions right um second question um
yeah sure um like we are all mentally
colonized you I very much even we uh
become extreme right still we are very
colonized uh even I was U looking for a
course here uh it was
introduction to machine learning it was
Mandarin Spanish Hindi was not there
even though a lot of us watch so I want
to ask that uh indic Renaissance is one
of the things to overcome it do we
really need it and if we read it that
what are the things the sources we need
to do
it so what you are saying is very true I
will you you will find books being
printed in very small obscure languages
like SW
or God knows what but it will not be
done in Hindi if you if you buy a laptop
you will not find a keyboard in the
Hindi or Indian languages but if you go
to Afghanistan you will find a keyboard
in PTO so it is something that like we
have not done enough to ensure that our
culture is respected and it is it is uh
it is given the sufficient amount of of
of space that it it deserves right and
that is all consequence of mental
colonization like you clearly point out
and and what it causes is that because
of because of this situation Indians
lack self-confidence Indians lack
self-belief when Indians go abroad they
feel that everyone is superior to them
when some Foreigner comes to India they
think that the Indians think that this
person is better than us because they
speak English with a different accent
and they have a white skin Etc and so on
so all of these things are causing
Indians to
uh lack self-respect self-belief and all
that you know so this needs to be
addressed it it has to happen through
the government we can keep demanding it
but unless the government that we have
elected unless the government takes
certain steps and actions nothing's
going to happen so I hope that when the
government decides the time is right
hopefully soon they will start doing
something about this and that would be
good for the
country can I ask another question okay
one more go ahead
okay so it's going to be a little
personal one like you are a physicist
I'm first time talking to a scientist
like this face to face um um whenever we
do something creative there's like a box
uh you think hard think hard you try to
tap it I call it kind of Genius box so
what is your way to tap it and open it
and get the creative idea because it's
very hard to do
it itust I
don't I don't know I mean
I think it's just something that every
every individual has a certain
personality a certain kind of character
some people are naturally creative
naturally curious Etc you know what the
truth is that every little child is
brilliant everybody is born brilliant
everybody is naturally curious everybody
is every little child is curious about
things and every little child is
creative it is the education system that
hammers that
creativity
and out of the child you know and over
over the years we we stop thinking
creatively and we stopped being curious
because we are not allowed to ask
questions and so on so I think in my
case that did not happen I did not allow
the education system to break me so I
have been able to retain the Curiosity
and the creativity Etc I don't think I'm
an exceptionally brilliant person like
some people claim and all I'm just a
regular person I just have found the
right way of thinking uh so so that's
what I can answer I think everybody body
can do it everybody can be creative if
we just recondition reprogram our minds
everybody can do it so that's my answer
to love your work sir thank you sir
thank you for thank you so much thank
you thank you bye-
bye okay let me take a couple more
questions uh let us bring
in smriti hi hi
sir uh I would like to know more
about hi
hi hi yeah go on I would like to know
about aala by
Hulker aala by Hulker
yes so aalia B Hulker was a prominent
Queen I think she
belonged to a marata family marata
Dynasty and uh see I I don't remember
the exact dates and all but I believe
that her husband died when uh she was
quite young she had one child child one
son
and after once her husband died she U
felt hopeless and helpless and she
expressed the desire to commit Sati and
join her husband in the afterlife but
her father-in-law was able to persuade
her not to do that and then she became
the the queen of the of the of the
Kingdom the and she went on to become a
very very prominent Queen somebody who
achieved a lot she rebuilt a lot of
temples that the Turks had destroyed
including in Varanasi and other places
and she ensured that her people uh had
the right kind of justice and all there
was a time when people if even if they
became Rich they used to try and hide
their wealth so that the so that the
rulers will not try and tax them too
much but she made it very clear that she
was not going to unnecessarily tax
people and you can actually be rich and
it is good for the country it's good for
the society that people become
prosperous and on so uh she did a great
deal of good in her life and after she
passed away she is even today remembered
as as a saintly person so that's what I
can tell you in very brief about the
great Maharani aala
Hulker uh may I ask another question
please go ahead yes um you mentioned
this earlier that um Cal plus even
though it was Indian uh others have
taken credits for it even the Hindu
numerals are called Arabic numerals and
there are so many examples for that uh
can government do something about it
like can they form a committee and you
know give proper credits like claim
it absolutely absolutely the government
has all the money all the resources
India is one of the wealthiest countries
in the world the indan government is one
of the wealthiest governments in the
world it has all the power power it can
constitute a committee it can it can uh
create a new Institute of of research
historical research the government can
do whatever it wants it has the
resources we have sufficient numbers of
historians in the country especially
young researchers who can get together
and and and do things a priority without
the burden of the colonial baggage that
the older restaurant have so I think the
government can do it tomorrow if they
wish to and we can uh um research all of
the all of these uh these chapters of
our history and ReDiscover the correct
chronology of the development of Indian
science of of Indian mathematics from
algebra to trigonometry to calculus to
infinite series and all that I think
it's something that can be done if
enough resources are provided and the
infrastructure has put in place so I
think yes the government certainly can
do it I have been saying that the
government should do these things I hope
that one of these days they will decide
to do it but yeah you are right this
should
happen
yeah is there any way we could do
something like apart from putting it out
on the
internet I don't see anything
else see individuals can do it I people
like me we we talk about history uh we
could possibly write articles for write
books Etc but what needs to happen is
that number of good talented people need
to to come together put their heads
together combine forces because when
multiple people get together the the
effect is much larger and for that you
need some sort of leadership to bring a
number of different people together and
you need the right kind of resources
because if you want people to work on
something you have to pay them for it
right because people need to earn
something you know so so that's why the
right kind of leadership needs to be put
in place we need leadership and we need
funds if that is available we can do
it right thank you so much sir I'm very
grateful most welcome thank you so much
thanks bye thanks
bye okay Whom Shall I call
now please hello sir hello hi I'm I'm
from like past 20 minutes uh sir I'm
your big fan I watch all your series sir
my I have two questions yes sir I'm a
and I'm from Punjab okay so one question
I have
uh you you have mentioned many times
that when you study history and you read
geopolitics you start learning about
patterns so my question is like what
pattern do you see right now and what
phase we are going through and what is
relevant uh right now that has already
occurred in the
past the pattern that I'm witnessing
right now is that we seem to be
back in a fa in a certain part phase of
history that is reminiscent of the
1930s so if you go back to the
1930s you will see that the world was
realigning very quickly new uh Power
centers had emerged Germany was rearming
itself the Western world no Germany was
part of the western world but the UK was
a very pacifistic at the time they did
not want to offend Germany too much and
Hitler was you know re rebuilding
Germany as a great military power the
Soviets were another Force there so
today what I see is that the Chinese are
showing the same kind of behavioral
pattern today that Nazi Germany was
showing in the 1930s so history I say is
cyclical it occurs again and again in
according to certain patterns and that's
the kind of pattern I'm seeing right
now okay thank you thank you so much sir
and one more question sir what do what
is the contribution of Indians in
geology over the
ancient yes
sir uh that is a question that has come
out of left wheel I don't know uh
geology is not a science that I have
studied in any significant detail have
Indians contributed I not that I know of
unfortunately not that I know of but I I
am sure that I don't have sufficient
knowledge this is one field that I
haven't studied so
even the best of my knowledge yeah yeah
you know so sorry for that I don't I
cannot answer this question sufficiently
well thank you so much sir nice to meet
you sir nice to meet you thank you thank
you bye
thank all right whom do we bring in
let's bring in karik hi
karik yes
sir sir am I audible
now did I take you earlier again are you
back yes sir actually yes sir actually
my uh internet problem was there okay
pleas yes yes I can hear you please ask
your
question and we have to take our credits
which we were deprived of so sir uh do
you think with secularism can India uh
get progress in the future years and
what should be the type of government
which uh which should be very good for a
country like India
okay good question I think secularism is
not the right choice for India
secularism is going to take India
backwards not forwards that's question
that's answer number one uh what is the
best type of governance in India I think
we need to
reintroduce the kind of governance
system we had during the Maha janapada
era we had a hybrid form of democracy in
which you have would have a a leader a
long-term leader who would govern the
country on behalf of the people you
would also have a democratically elected
setup and you would have a Judiciary
that would actually be subservient to
the people who would not Lord about or
the people and so on so it was a a very
interesting form of democracy
democracy as as our prime minister has
recently said is was born in India
democracy emerged out of ancient India
way before the Greeks invented it so
that is something we need to look at and
maybe try and recreate that system
because the current democratic system
that we have today the so-called
democracy that we have it doesn't serve
the people it doesn't really take the
country forward there is too much
infighting there is too much Division
and the entire energy of the country is
wasted in this internal friction instead
of all being aligned in the same
direction so we need to definitely
reform our system of governance
Administration and democracy so I think
maybe we should consider the Maha
janapada era more seriously and try to
replicate that and see how that works
right and Sir uh I am I am a student of
uh I am currently studying in class 11
and I had uh very much interest in
history but I was not able to opt it
because uh the the history which was
there in the textbooks which I had to
study in class 11th and 12th that
not so sir like uh I love history and I
love to know much more about history sir
uh I had seen your video about the
history books sir I had read that Al
Bashan book and as you said there are
many uh wrong things written which need
to be corrected uh like that of RN
Invasion Theory sir what uh what are the
other books uh which should I prefer and
I have uh gone through all your episodes
it was really helpful
thank you uh listen I cannot tell you
where to start there are hundreds of
history books thousands of history books
um so maybe you can start with the
history of Civilization by Will Durant
maybe that is one possibility or maybe
one choice if you can find that series
of
books but uh you know I I have read so
many books and things that I cannot
think right now of uh like two or three
books that I can give you right now that
you can start off with but try look at
the video I think I've given a number of
history books recommendations you can
use that as a starting point and uh you
should start with some overview of
History maybe overview of world history
there are many books like that or
overview of Indian history there will be
lots of wrong things but that's how you
start and eventually you'll start
figuring out what is right what is wrong
so you know it's it takes a lot of
reading there's no one book or five
books that you can read this if you want
to understand world history and Indian
history properly it's going to take take
you a lot of time and a lot of reading
so read as much as you can that's what I
will suggest right okay sir thank you
sir thank you so much thank you nice
meeting you
bye okay let's bring in wasu hi wasu
hello sir hi hi I great it's honor to
mute you sir thank you so much nice to
meet you so sir my question is that I am
a student of Class 8 so in our books
like history we have seen sir in history
they says that mols were very great but
you says they were just a turkic
Invaders who just looted India so so sir
why they are telling us this that they
were very great and they were
revolutionary like
this so that is the agenda that these
Marxist historians have had for a very
long time see uh during the nouvian era
of India's post Independence phase uh we
know that Neu was a mentally colonized
gentleman he was a
wonderful nice Chacha or whatever we
call him but he was mentally colonized
he was an angile he loved the British
very much he owed his entire political
career to the British and he was also an
enormous fan of the muls of the Turks
who invaded and occupied India for a
very long time you can read what he has
written about them he was quite um he he
portrayed them in a very good way Etc so
so because he he was in power that's why
the historians wanted to please him and
eventually what happened was that um
historians of the Marxist persuasion
were were given the role of writing
India's history textbooks and today if
you look at the Indian academic system
there is a strangle hold of marxist
academics in the academic system so the
entire perspective they're putting
forward is a colonial perspective they
they want to essentially eradicate
Indian culture and Hinduism from India
and one of the ways of doing it is to
make Indians feel that their culture is
inferior because we have always lost
everything which is not true at all but
by portraying it that way in the
official history textbooks it puts a
certain kind of mental conditioning into
the head of every child so there are
political agendas and other agendas at
work over here which is why they have
been glorifying India's Invaders
occupiers and
oppressors uh thank you sir sir my next
question is Sir s since when and why did
the C system started in
India yeah that is a topic I will take
up
separately uh it is it is portrayed in
such a way that India has been a
horrible misogynistic country in which
women were burned alive after their
husbands died I just gave the example of
Maharani aala by Hulker who was
persuaded by her father-in-law not to do
that and she went on to become a great
Queen one of the greatest queens of the
past 10,000 years and there are I mean
there are so many data points I can give
you that prove that there is no such
pattern I mean you had the Bengal famine
you had you had famine after famine that
was engineered artificially by the
British during the British occupation of
India in which so many people died
including men did their wives all commit
Sati nobody did right so there are so
many examples that completely prove this
wrong but it is something that our
history textbooks and historians keep on
harping on but it's not true right so
that's last question is Sir from where
did the swastic symbol originated and
why did Hitler used it in his flag yeah
I'm going to make a separate video about
that it's a very very detailed analysis
that I have to do to answer your
questions so I cannot answer it in in
brief but I will make a video about it
in the future right thank you thank you
very much sir thank you so much thank
you thank you bye bye sir bye okay I
have taken it very far I will take one
more viewer one more person I apologize
in advance to everybody else who has
been waiting I really apologize it's
impossible for me to bring everybody in
I will bring in one
person whom shall I bring in one person
one person I'll bring in sankalp hi
sankalp all right uh har Krishna sir
uh I have this uh doubt regarding see uh
you we have been talking about China's
economic progress and and also their
economic boom so are there any chances
that they are also falsifying their
figures or just ere
exaggerating absolutely absolutely it is
a very much a possibility so right now
China's economy is slowing down that is
the data that we already have it was
growing at the rate of 10 plus per per
year for a very long time now the
official figures the official Chinese
Communist Party figures uh the data the
statistics is it says that the Chinese
economy is growing at 5 to 6% per year
and yet if you examine the signs and
symptoms coming out of China the signs
of recession the ever Grand crisis and
so on so forth the actual figure seems
to be like one or two% of growth so I am
I it's not only me who is saying that
lots of economists have remarked about
this you will find people writing about
this right now today economists writing
about it and China observers writing
about it that China's economy seems to
be growing only at 1 or 2% per year they
are falsifying the figures and China
seems to be headed towards recession and
a crisis and that is actually bad news
for the world because it may uh lead the
Chinese Communist party to take certain
very stupid and rash actions that could
plunge the world into war so yeah you
are right it is certainly possible that
the Chinese Communist party is
falsifying the economic
data all right uh so last question for
today yeah um sir one of the viewers
also said this that maybe we failed to
propagate our the concept of Hinduism so
do you think that Ison you must be
familiar with it are on on that part or
they are just brainwashing the western
westerners or just spreading the
awareness of
Hinduism so you know what I haven't
studied esor and great I'm I'm aware of
the fact that they have branches in many
parts of the world in the North America
in Europe as well Russia as well I
haven't studied their teachings their
writings and U their philosophy so I
can't really answer
whether they I mean what what kind of
Hinduism do they represent what kind of
Dharma do they represent are they
portraying it correctly I I can't answer
it because I haven't studied it I
haven't been part of their whatever it
is that they're they're doing but as
long as they are propagating Dharma
faith fully I think it's a very good
thing because it will give more exposure
to the world to Indian teachings as long
as it is done faithfully and accurately
so that's what I can tell you but I
haven't personally seen it or examined
it in in sufficient detail to to give
you a a judgment a value judgment of
what what they're doing you
know thank you very much sir thank you
so much nice to meet you thanks bye
bye okay my friends I AP apologize to
everybody who is waiting in the wings I
am so sorry I I have run out of time but
we will do this
again uh so so yeah I'm going to have to
stop it here those of you who are
waiting I'm very sorry but I will try
and take you up next time so this was
great fun this was more fun than I
expected talking to all of you live and
I think I will do it again so until next
time thank you so much it was a
wonderful episode 50 and this is going
to continue we're going to keep on doing
this these live Q&A sessions as long as
it is possible thank you so much for
watching and I will see you in the next
episode thank you so much and bye